Hello friends, I am Ravindra and
welcome to my YouTube channel. I am
here with you guys with
a very important topic related to motor insurance,
which
we all should know about. As
in the previous video, we talked about the third party policy
and the first party policy, what is the
difference between the two, what is covered and what is
not covered.
We talked about all these things in the previous video.
If you have not seen it,
you can see it by clicking on the i button.
But suppose you have renewed the policy and
purchased it online
and you want the first one, yes, this third
party policy of this water policy. The
policy has come to you for your vehicle. Now
how will you know what all is
covered in it, which policy is it that you get?
Sometimes it happens by mistake that you
wanted a third party policy, this third party
policy, but later you come to know that there is a lot of
delay in the second one, so
how will you find out by looking at your policy which is that third party
policy, this first party policy, policy,
policy, to identify it.  For example, I will
show you some policies here
and you will have a separate identity for the bike
and there will be a driver, there will be a third
party identity, how much is the value of your vehicle,
how will we
find out about this thing inside ourselves, let's start the video,
like here you can see which is the
doctors policy, which is a car policy,
Maruti Alto K10, it is exactly the
make-up option of excise and the C deficit is 98,
so in this way, from here it becomes clear that the
make and model of my vehicle is
written here, now we will
find out which policy is this, third
party or first party policy and
what is the value of our vehicle, so see, there are
two ways to differentiate between third party policy and first policy and first of all,
here you
can tell the value, that is, a value of your vehicle, it is 1
lakh 54 thousand 701,
now if this value is attached to the vehicle, then
suppose you have hundred percent and the
same is the policy of your vehicle, first
party policy or comprehensive policy,
if the ID also values  In case
of improvement in the car, your policy
will be a third party policy. Some insurance
companies directly put the value of the vehicle
here for ₹1, so if
your body value is bad or ₹1, then
understand that this policy of your car is
required for third party. After this, there is another way to
save it. You will come down here,
in the film, there will be their section and
damage cover is here and in the middle section there is
third party cover.
Pradhan Pradeep Sareen, so it will be in both your
policies. If the party is kept in third party, then it
is compulsory from the government side. The policy of your
car should be at least. If you see the
basic premium here, then it is Rs. 600.
Here is your third party premium
and below it, you will keep the PA and driver cover.
Here, 325 is the useful insurance of 15 lakhs. In case of
accident of the governor and driver of the car, this is the back cover here, the
rest are the two passenger legal liability to
employers. In front of all these, you will see if your
premium is 0, then good.  This is written in your policy
but this policy is not your cover.
Different companies have different London formats
so this thing can go up and down, you
can change it there but the method will
remain the same as it is written in front
in Meghnad's car policy.
Hey, look in the A section and
see here in the debit premium,
your basic premium is 2231 in that 42 paise, so
this condom cream is of which person for your car, the
person who has paid 1 lakh 54 thousand 700,
according to that, this is your other tablets cream
or this cream for the security of your car,
this is your anger, so it
changed from here and behind this there is a
voice of cow no claim bonus or discount, now
any discount is given and if you have
not faced any problem in the previous policies then
here you have got a discount of fifty percent
and its value becomes
1110 paise, 70 paise, you have got this
discount, if you want to know
how much you get,
in which year you have to make a claim, then in this way you can
insure it.  There is an increase and how you
can get it, for this you can click on the i button and
see it in the second video or two, I will
add a link at this time, by going there
you can get complete information about NCB,
how you can transfer NC of
old vehicle also to your vehicle,
I have explained all these things in detail,
so here you will find section 1 and
section 2, the total premium
here is 7165 for 3570 but the
premium you have offered is 6147, which
means some more things have been added in it,
so keep scrolling down here,
you will see here, the cover
is there above or it is also called like cover
or it is said in specific and
in normal language it is also called bumper-to-bumper,
so here you can find out whether there is
Devda Express in your policy
or not, here 1700 ₹1 is your
minimum here, just from night shift, this is a
first party policy or comprehensive
package policy in which G road  Grave s0
depression cover is also included here, this
makes your final amount 6147 965,
now see here, there is a bike policy,
here
Abhay TVS XL Super Acid, this is your bike
and here the C capacity is 78, here you will
see 8300 air developed, the vehicle
may be old, due to which the
value of the vehicle is less here, this number is
chassis number, here you will see the policy
number as I told you m13, in this way
here is the policy number and you can see
about the basic premium, here
your first party's is 782 rupees,
so here this is the back cover, the rest are pet
passenger vehicle liability to employers, in
front of all these you will see that your 0 crore, so
even though it is written in your policy that this
policy does not cover you, after this here
in the basic premium pande, its vehicle's premium is
₹90 and 95 paisa which is the liability
premium, the basic prem is 94 95 paisa,
so here you will see that today I have
pimped  It was told that there is not much difference between third party and clean
party policy.
If you want to save 944 paise, then
you can suffer a lot of loss because of this. You
can see here that the
company has given you coverage of the car for 8300 rupees.
If there is any damage to the car, the car gets
stolen, it gets totaled, it catches fire,
in that case you can
get maximum coverage up to 8300 and how much did
you get it for, 94-95 paise. So you can see that there is
not much difference in third
party verification, especially if your car becomes
old or if it is bike insurance, the
outer limit of the car, as you saw, is of 100 something, there is a
difference of a few thousand rupees.
This is not manufactured here. You can see here that
this is a 2011 bike, an old bike, the
real ID is less here and in this,
when it is an old bike or a car, it is
for 5 years, hence vibration cover is available, so you can see
that the back cover will not be available here. You
can see by scrolling down here, if I
show you, the section which was there, hence
in the policy  I saw it, it is not here, the next
episode you cover is not edited in it, total
love is received for years 1037 uses, this is the
policy which is the first policy of your bike, in
this way we can check any party and
find out
what all is covered and slanted in our policy, it is the first
artificial or third party policy and
how to check the product policy,
I have told you the price of the vehicle,
IDBI receiver delete value, if you
want to know how it is calculated, then
I have given the length of the video
in the description or you
can watch the full video by clicking on the i button, in that I will
tell you in detail how the ID is calculated,
so I hope you must have understood
how we can identify the first party positive third party policy
through our hair, if you have
any questions related to this video, then you
can ask by commenting, we will definitely answer it
or you
can message us on Instagram, I have given the test of this
in the description, so I hope
you must have liked this video, if you
liked the video then please like the video  Do do it
and to watch such educational videos,
do subscribe to my channel.
I will meet you in the next video, till then
bye a k
a